shivtr.com 2018-09-05

# Privacy Policy for Shivtr

#### Shivtr is committed to protecting the privacy of our users:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  * In our products, we aim to make it easy for you to control what’s visible to the public and what’s kept private.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals:

Shivtr (“Shivtr”) operates several websites including shivtr.com and games.shivtr.com. It is Shivtr’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Shivtr collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Shivtr’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Shivtr’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Shivtr may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Shivtr also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users posting content on Shivtr.com sites. Shivtr only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that poster IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the site where the content was posted.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Shivtr’s websites choose to interact with Shivtr in ways that require Shivtr to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Shivtr gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a Shivtr account to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Shivtr – by purchasing a Premium plan, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Shivtr collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Shivtr. Shivtr does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Shivtr may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Shivtr may monitor the most popular sites on Shivtr.com or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. Shivtr may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Shivtr does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Google Analytics

Shivtr uses a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit and when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information from Google Analytics only to improve this site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html). If you do not want to participate in Google Analytics, you may also download the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Shivtr discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Shivtr’s behalf or to provide services available at Shivtr’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Shivtr’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Shivtr will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Shivtr discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Shivtr believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Shivtr, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a Shivtr website and have supplied your email address, Shivtr may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Shivtr and our products. We primarily use our product blog to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Shivtr takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Shivtr uses cookies to help Shivtr identify and track visitors, their usage of Shivtr website, and their website access preferences. Shivtr visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Shivtr’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Shivtr’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Advertising

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads on Shivtr.
  * Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to Shivtr and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [Google's ads preference manager](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/).

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Shivtr may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Shivtr’s sole discretion. Shivtr encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

#### Change log

  * Feb 5, 2016: Added the "Google Analytics" section
  * November 5, 2013: Privacy Policy updated to be clearer.
  * June 24, 2011: Company renamed from “MMO Guildsites” to “Shivtr”.
